




  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python Objects :: CC 210 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc210/07-objects/08-python/</link>
    <description>Objects in Python</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc210/07-objects/08-python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Instance Classes</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc210/07-objects/08-python/01-instance-classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc210/07-objects/08-python/01-instance-classes/</guid>
      <description>Now that we understand the basics of what classes and objects are in object-oriented programming, let’s look at how to create these items in Python.&#xA;Creating an Instance Class Creating a class in Python is very similar to creating a function. We can simply use the class keyword, followed by an identifier for the class and a colon. The class definition, like all Python definitions and code-bodies, is indented.&#xA;While it is not required, it is recommended to place just a single class in each file, with the filename matching the name of the class, followed by the .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Objects &amp; Initialization</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc210/07-objects/08-python/02-initialization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc210/07-objects/08-python/02-initialization/</guid>
      <description>Of course, our classes are not very useful at this point because they don’t include any attributes or methods. Including instance attributes in an object class is one of the their basic uses, so let’s start there.&#xA;Types of Attributes There are two types of attributes: Class and Instance.&#xA;Instance attributes are variables that “belong” to the instance. It makes sense that a Student-object owns its own name.&#xA;We will deffer discussion of class attributes to a later module.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instances &amp; Testing</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc210/07-objects/08-python/03-instances-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc210/07-objects/08-python/03-instances-testing/</guid>
      <description>Your class should now look something like this, although your default values may be different:&#xA;class Ingredient: def __init__(self): self.name = &#34;butter&#34; self.amount = .25 self.units = &#34;cups&#34;As classes grow large you will want to test methods as you add them. In CC 410 we will learn about test frameworks and will write formal tests in parallel with project development.&#xA;For now we will follow the convention of a __TEST(cls) method.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instance Methods</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc210/07-objects/08-python/04-instance-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc210/07-objects/08-python/04-instance-methods/</guid>
      <description>We can also add additional methods to our classes. These methods are used either to modify the attributes of the class or to perform actions based on the attributes stored in the class. Finally, we can even use those methods to perform actions on data provided as arguments. In essence, the sky is the limit with methods in classes, so we’ll be able to do just about anything we need to do in these methods.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Driver Class</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc210/07-objects/08-python/05-driver-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc210/07-objects/08-python/05-driver-class/</guid>
      <description>The Driver class is much simpler. It has one feature, a class method main(cls, args). Everything that needs to be done will be done in the main method. A template might be&#xA;import sys class Driver: @classmethod def main(cls, args): pass if __name__ == &#34;__main__&#34;: Driver.main(sys.argv) Decorators in Python Previously we ave been using the decorator1 @staticmethod for main. It turns out that Python implements “static methods” very differently than most other languages.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putting it All Together</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc210/07-objects/08-python/06-putting-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc210/07-objects/08-python/06-putting-together/</guid>
      <description>First set the default values in Ingredient.__init() to: “flour”. 2.75, “cups”.&#xA;Next lets write a driver program which takes 2 command line arguments, a scale factor and a units string, and prints out the ingredient list for sugar cookies. The basic ingredients are&#xA;i1 (flour&#34;, 2.75, “cups”) i2 (“butter”, 1, “cups”) i3 (“sugar”, 1.5, “cups”) i4 (“baking powder”, 2.6, “ml”) i5 (“baking soda”, 15.0, “ml”) i5 (“vanilla extract”, 15.0, “ml”) A typical run might look like:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s Next</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc210/07-objects/08-python/07-next/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc210/07-objects/08-python/07-next/</guid>
      <description>There is no “project” for this module. Instead the basics of object-classes as well as the use of objects will be reinforced in the next few modules covering aggregate data, strings, exceptions and file system interactions.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>