




	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Java Inheritance on CC 210 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/13-inheritance/06-java/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Java Inheritance on CC 210 Textbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/13-inheritance/06-java/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Method Overriding</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/13-inheritance/06-java/02-method-overriding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/13-inheritance/06-java/02-method-overriding/</guid>
      <description>Video Materials
Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve created some classes that follow different inheritance relationships, let&amp;rsquo;s explore how we can use those relationships to change some methods in each class through the use of method overriding.
Vehicle Class First, let&amp;rsquo;s look at a couple of methods in the Vehicle class, the move() and describe() methods. As we might recall, the describe() method is an abstract method since it is in italicized text in the UML diagram.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polymorphism</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/13-inheritance/06-java/04-polymorphism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/13-inheritance/06-java/04-polymorphism/</guid>
      <description>Video Materials
Note: this video contains errors in the UML diagram, these errors have been fixed below.
Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve learned how to build the structure needed for classes to inherit attributes and methods from other classes, let&amp;rsquo;s explore how we can use those classes in our code.
Polymorphism Earlier, we defined polymorphism as &amp;ldquo;the condition of occurring in several different forms&amp;rdquo;1. In code, this allows us to create an object of a child class, and then store it in the data type for the parent class.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abstract Classes</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/13-inheritance/06-java/06-abstract-classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/13-inheritance/06-java/06-abstract-classes/</guid>
      <description>Video Materials
Note: this video contains errors in the UML diagram, these errors have been fixed below.
Another major feature of class inheritance is the ability to define a method in a parent class, but not provide any code that implements that function. In effect, we are saying that all objects of that type must include that method, but it is up to the child classes to provide the code.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Worked Example</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/13-inheritance/06-java/08-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/13-inheritance/06-java/08-example/</guid>
      <description>Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve seen how to build classes that can inherit attributes and methods from other classes, let&amp;rsquo;s work through a simple example program together to see how it all works in practice. The code in this program will be very simple, because the purpose is to explore how we can use the structure of inheritance in our programs.
Problem Statement First, let&amp;rsquo;s start with a problem statement. In this problem, we are going to build a program that will help us find an object in a toolbox based on several criteria provided from the user.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Class Inheritance</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/13-inheritance/06-java/01-class-inheritance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/13-inheritance/06-java/01-class-inheritance/</guid>
      <description>Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve learned a bit about the theory behind inheritance in object-oriented programming, let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the code and see how we can accomplish this in Java.
For these examples, we&amp;rsquo;ll be implementing the following UML diagram:
Italics &amp;amp; Hash Symbols The UML diagram above includes some items that we haven&amp;rsquo;t discussed yet. Don&amp;rsquo;t panic! We&amp;rsquo;ll cover them as they become relevant in this module.
For now, feel free to ignore the fact that methods are italicized.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protected Access</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/13-inheritance/06-java/03-protected-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/13-inheritance/06-java/03-protected-access/</guid>
      <description>Working with inherited classes also gives us an opportunity to learn about how data can be secured in the parent class so that any child class can easily access it, without any external class being able to do so.
Protected Attributes In Java, we can simply use the protected keyword as a security modifier, just like we learned how to use private and public in an earlier module. In effect, anything marked as protected in Java will be accessible to the class in which it is declared, as well as to any child classes, but not to any other classes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Type</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/13-inheritance/06-java/05-data-type/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/13-inheritance/06-java/05-data-type/</guid>
      <description>Of course, polymorphism can make things a bit more complicated when it comes to determining exactly what type of object is stored in a variable. Thankfully, Java includes a few easy ways to determine what type of object is really stored in a variable, as well as ways that we can convert the types if needed.
Determining Data Type Let&amp;rsquo;s go back to the previous example from the last page, where we had placed all of our objects in an array.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Inheritance</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/13-inheritance/06-java/07-multiple-inheritance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/13-inheritance/06-java/07-multiple-inheritance/</guid>
      <description>Finally, we can also build classes that are able to inherit from multiple parent classes. In Java, this is done through the use of interfaces.
The Diamond Problem Before we can really understand the importance of multiple inheritance, we must first discuss the &amp;ldquo;Diamond Problem.&amp;rdquo; This is a very common example in object-oriented programming, and it is used to describe one of the common pitfalls for multiple inheritance in programming.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>