




	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python Hello World Tutorial on CC 210 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/01-object-oriented-programming/07-python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python Hello World Tutorial on CC 210 Textbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/01-object-oriented-programming/07-python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/01-object-oriented-programming/07-python/02-hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/01-object-oriented-programming/07-python/02-hello-world/</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video
According to tradition, the first computer program that we cover in any language is a simple program called &amp;ldquo;Hello World!&amp;rdquo; The entire goal of the program is to demonstrate what it takes to create our first program from scratch in the language, and get to the point where we can print the message of our choice to the screen. While that sounds very simple, it is actually a pretty big first step toward learning how to write our own programs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running the Program</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/01-object-oriented-programming/07-python/03-running-the-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/01-object-oriented-programming/07-python/03-running-the-program/</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video
Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve written our first Python program, we must run the program to see the fruits of our labors.
Terminal Codio includes a built-in Linux terminal, which allows us to perform actions directly on a command-line interface. We can access the Terminal in many ways:
Selecting the Tools menu, then choosing the Terminal option Pressing SHIFT + ALT + T in any Codio window (you can customize this shortcut in your Codio user preferences) Pressing the Open Terminal icon in the file tree Additionally, some pages may already open a terminal window for us in the left-hand pane, as this page so helpfully does.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Debugging</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/01-object-oriented-programming/07-python/04-debugging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/01-object-oriented-programming/07-python/04-debugging/</guid>
      <description>Of course, when developing a computer program, there are always times when things don&amp;rsquo;t quite work the way we&amp;rsquo;d like them to. Let&amp;rsquo;s review a few of the common errors and how to solve them.
Wrong Interpreter When working with Python, one of the most common mistakes is typing the python command when we actually mean to use the python3 command. This would cause our program to be interpreted with the Python 2 interpreter instead of the Python 3 interpreter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>History of Python</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/01-object-oriented-programming/07-python/01-history-of-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/01-object-oriented-programming/07-python/01-history-of-python/</guid>
      <description>1
Python was originally developed in the late 1980s and early 1990s by Guido van Rossum as a successor to the ABC programming language used at the research lab where he worked. Some initial goals of this language were to be able to interface with the Amoeba operating system and to include functions for exception handling.
Guido &amp;amp; Monty According to the official Python FAQ, Python was named in honor of Monty Python&amp;rsquo;s Flying Circus, as Guido van Rossum was reading scripts from the TV show while he was originally implementing parts of Python.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>