




	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Java Exceptions on CC 210 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/10-exceptions/06-java/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Java Exceptions on CC 210 Textbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/10-exceptions/06-java/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Common Exceptions &amp; Errors</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/10-exceptions/06-java/01-common/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/10-exceptions/06-java/01-common/index.html</guid>
      <description>Before we learn about how to detect and handle exceptions in Java, let&amp;rsquo;s review some of the common exceptions and errors we may see in our programs. Each of the headers below is the name of an exception in Java, which is represented by a particular class in the Java programming language.
Exception Java 8 API Reference Every exception that can be handled in Java is a subtype of the Exception class.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Checked vs. Unchecked Exceptions</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/10-exceptions/06-java/02-unchecked/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/10-exceptions/06-java/02-unchecked/index.html</guid>
      <description>Beyond the difference between exceptions and errors we&amp;rsquo;ve already discussed, Java also makes a distinction between two types of exceptions, checked exceptions and unchecked exceptions. Let&amp;rsquo;s look more closely at each of these groups below.
Checked Exceptions A checked exception is detected by the Java compiler. When it detects a checked exception, the compiler then looks to see if the exception will be detected and handled within the code. If not, it will then check to see if the method containing that code includes a throws clause1 at the end of the method declaration that includes this particular exception.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Try-Catch</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/10-exceptions/06-java/03-try-catch/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/10-exceptions/06-java/03-try-catch/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video
Video Materials
Programs written in Java can have many exceptions occur on a regular basis. Thankfully, as we learned earlier, it is possible to detect and handle these exceptions in our code directly, in order to prevent our program crashing and causing the user more stress. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how we can perform this step in Java. A Try-Catch construct is synonymous with &amp;ldquo;handler&amp;rdquo;.
Try-Catch In Java, we use a Try-Catch construct to detect and handle exceptions in our code.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Throw and Throws</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/10-exceptions/06-java/04-throws/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/10-exceptions/06-java/04-throws/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video
Video Materials
Beyond catching exceptions, there are a few other important concepts to learn related to exceptions. Let&amp;rsquo;s go over a couple of them.
Throws When the Java compiler finds a checked exception, we must either surround that code in a Try-Catch statement, or we must declare the exception to be thrown by adding throws to our method declaration, followed by the exception type.
Here&amp;rsquo;s an example:
import java.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finally</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/10-exceptions/06-java/05-finally/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/10-exceptions/06-java/05-finally/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video
Video Materials
When dealing with exceptions in our code, sometimes we have an operation that must be executed, even if the earlier code throws an exception. In that case, we can use the finally keyword to make sure that the correct code is executed.
Finally To understand how the finally keyword works, let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at an example:
import java.util.Scanner; import java.lang.NumberFormatException; import java.lang.IllegalArgumentException; public class Finally{ public static void main(String[] args){ Scanner reader; reader = new Scanner(System.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Try with Resources</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/10-exceptions/06-java/06-resources/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/10-exceptions/06-java/06-resources/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video
Video Materials
Lastly, Java includes a special type of Try-Catch statement, known as a Try with Resources statement, that can perform some of the work typically handled by the finally block.
Try with Resources Let&amp;rsquo;s look at an example of a Try with Resources statement:
import java.util.Scanner; import java.io.File; import java.lang.NumberFormatException; import java.io.FileNotFoundException; public class Resources{ public static void main(String[] args){ try( Scanner reader = new Scanner(new File(&amp;#34;input.txt&amp;#34;)) ){ int x = Integer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/10-exceptions/06-java/07-best-practices/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/10-exceptions/06-java/07-best-practices/index.html</guid>
      <description>Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve seen lots of information about how to throw, catch, and handle exceptions in Java, it is a great time to discuss some of the best practices we can apply in our code to make it as readable and bulletproof as possible. While these aren&amp;rsquo;t strict rules that must be followed all the time, they are great things to keep in mind as we write code that deals with exceptions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Worked Example</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/10-exceptions/06-java/08-example/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc210/10-exceptions/06-java/08-example/index.html</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s work through an entire example program together to see how we can build programs that handle exceptions quickly and easily, without allowing the program to crash when invalid input is received.
Problem Statement Consider the following problem statement for a driver-class program Example.java:
Write a program to accept a list of numbers, one per line from the terminal.
The numbers can either be positive whole numbers or positive floating point numbers.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>